the start of today's episode is a bit of
a strange one i've been trying to help
scar him get his cat jelly if you didn't
know scar in real life has a cat called
jelly and he won a competition to get
that cat in minecraft now here's the
thing beef has sent over a jelly but
it's already tamed and
i tried to help scar out here by
breeding one of my cats with the jelly
one and now i have a jelly he needs his
own cat to make this work and look at
him look how sad he is i'm gonna make
him even more sad instead of jelly with
a with a j it's gonna be jelly with a g
kelly
okay okay come on scott let's go get you
let's let's let's go get you a cat okay
so this is where i got my cats from
maybe there's another cat for scar right
here is that a cat is this cat
i've had a cat i found one i found one i
found one
yes
success
we've walked all the way here this car
is playing it's so safe
he's he's literally walking and this has
been a mission to get this cat here but
we're almost there
follow the fish
come on scar follow the fish i love the
way that it just pops out the back of my
head like
hey
there we go right we're ready
take the fish scar
make it happen
and he
he got the wrong
he got the wrong cat
[Laughter]
try again
try again this has been
we're so close to the end now this has
been genuinely like an hour mission to
get scar a jelly but this mission has
been going on way longer than just today
but we finally figured out how to do it
come on scar
yes
come on
he's gone
my mind is melting a little bit here
we've been standing here for about an
hour getting the wrong cat
come on scar
i did it once
and i got a jelly
he's gone
what is it with these cats and just
piecing out he's gonna go get it he's
like no he's not getting away from me
this time
you did it
yeah it's it's happened
it's happened
scar has finally got his jelly and it
only took two hours
oh my it's my cat
it's my it's my cat
i can't do
this is ridiculous why is it my cat
okay there's another jelly
it is it's done
it's done
[Laughter]
i could cry
scar i've got a gift for you
there you go it's a name tag for jelly
make it happen
make it happen this is a moment
chilly it's done
so now we have the real jelly
and the realer jelly
okay let's uh
let's go and work on my base i've had
i've had enough of cats for today i have
been
mega ultra mega ultra busy in here now i
haven't made any progress on the builds
because that's what i want to do a
little bit later on
what i've been doing
is sorting out this
as everyone knows
villagers
are kind of a nuisance and i
have moved
all of them from over here to over here
now this means i actually have a proper
functioning trade hall
for those of you that don't know what
that is it means i can essentially get a
lot of resources by spending time
trading
rather than collecting materials now
some of the things that i can get bricks
terracotta polish diorite golden carrots
in short
lots of things that i can put on the
barge now we actually started this
project during a live stream
earlier in the week
and that's kind of what this is for
because ren and i did a charity stream
for a charity called africa sos and we
very successfully raised way above the
rennes stinky we raised way above our
target a massive 80 000 pounds so if you
were watching if you donated thank you
very very much that money is going to be
put to some very good causes but i will
for now get rid of this and the link to
that live stream if you want to watch it
will be in the description as it is now
unlisted and it gives you a quick idea
of how much of a nuisance and how long
things like that take
so now that this very lengthy task is
out of the way
i want
to completely transform
this build now i'm friends with someone
called pearlescent moon and i have a
copy of this world on my uh private
server and she was just messing around
building some stuff and she came up with
an excellent design and i've edited it a
little bit but for the most part she
helped me
enormously and came up with some really
cool ideas so we're going to go into a
time lapse and we're going to completely
transform this based on pearlescent
moons designs with a few
with a view of my own little touches as
well
now before we go into this time lapse i
just want to say thank you pearl that
was really cool and if you want to see
more of what pearl can do in minecraft
there will be a link to her channel in
the description she's almost 100k it
would be really cool if you checked her
out after this video but anyway let's
head into a time lapse because i got so
inspired and i really really want to get
this done so
few hours work let's go
[Applause]
[Music]
so
wow
we
it is complete or at least as much as i
want to do i made this
in four
different building sessions to get this
done
and my oh my i really really like this
so thank you pearlescent moon for
helping me with some of the design parts
this is big is scar here scar
what have you done
how long have you been there hi yeah
high yourself okay so ignoring that i am
really really happy with how this has
come out
please let me know in the comments what
you think i love the fact that i can fly
around this i really like the fact that
this kind of makes up for the fact that
we're underground like
the roof and stuff has been properly
integrated and so it kind of gets away
with feeling like it's inside
this part
even though it's not even though this
will have like the technical farms and
such it kind of feels like you're going
inside there anyway just because of the
large pillars and the proper roof and
stuff and trust me
this is actually more space underground
than i would have got to fit
in this thing because of the really
strange shape that it's become
yeah you see i wouldn't have gotten away
with this quite as much this room would
not have been as grand in here at all
so all in all another chunk of the base
done
i never really do interior so that was a
bit of a hurdle for me my next task will
probably be tackling this thing
the other half we don't look at the back
i avoid the back this is probably one of
the first times you get to see it um in
its entirety because i've been
thoroughly thoroughly avoiding it but
this is gonna be a task that i
definitely do a bit later on
now that my item sorter is done i'm
going to off camera slowly start getting
rid of all of these chests here because
they are
really starting to get out of hand but i
mean that's just
tidying up in minecraft is very much
like tidying up in real life really
really boring and i don't want to do it
so even though i've got all the
equipment in here
to clean up my base i still don't want
to do it
i still don't want to do it i cannot
stop looking at this by the way i just
think it looks absolutely amazing one
thing that i've been able to do is get
myself lots of materials from these
villagers and i can use these to stock
up the barge
all it takes is well a couple hours
trading get some emeralds go over here
and
talk to batman
i'm batman
i think you mean g-man i then take my
emeralds and then i buy terra cotta or
quartz or whatever i want to stock brits
is another thing that i want to stock
and i've been slowly putting together
these bits of stock for the
barge itself because uh i've been
getting some messages from the other
hermit saying green you need more stock
so again we're going to stock up some
stuff at the shopping district and while
we're there why don't we check up on the
oh
really
man
i really need that last one
the competition is still there
phosphor mayor mumbo for mayor
it looks like people are really starting
to enter the race
okay well can someone please tell me
how did he get up there
there's no portal here how on earth did
he get up there
i feel like we need to put some more
mumbo for mare signs up everywhere
and i definitely need to get to work on
that headquarters but the first thing
we're going to do
is stock this up
we got four boxes of sand three boxes of
gravel
and two boxes of golden carrots and we
got a bit of profit as well so we'll pop
the investment in the barrel there
and i will let everyone know that this
is all stocked up and i'm afraid i am
now out of gravel and sand so this will
be the last stock for a little while
until i can get back to the grind for
those
stupid phantoms
yeah that's what i thought the redstone
shop that used to be in front of the
town hall
is now
the red zone over there and if i'm not
mistaken b-dubs made that and it looks
absolutely amazing i oh i love that that
is the cutest little airship i don't
know how it's flying but it's awesome oh
it's got a little oh it's got little
hoppers
very futuristic that looks amazing
absolutely amazing shopping district is
getting improved every single day but we
still need a mayor
someone who can be rid of the phantoms
and there truly is only one man for the
job
at the end of last episode we built up
this tiny little island and it's got the
current
mumbo jumbo for mayor
headquarters
the tiny shack
with nothing in it so another thing that
i definitely want to do today
is to start building at least the first
part
of the mumbo
headquarters
and there's one thing is for sure it's
definitely not gonna fit on this tiny
island so it may be on stilts i'm not
sure i haven't really got a good idea
that's why i built this shack in the
first place but i think
maybe if i just get into free flow i
could just go for it and see what
happens we only need to make one part of
it we can always make it bigger after so
let let's at least get a meeting room
ready for this because honestly i think
it's about time we told mumbo
that i'm uh i'm campaigning for him to
be mayor so let's get into it
[Music]
[Applause]
have you ever seen the sun set over a
mustache as magenta no
ruined
have you wait a minute have you ever
seen the sun rise over a mustache before
well there it is mumbo headquarters at
least
the start of it i think my plan is to
build based on our needs so instead of
building an enormous headquarters with
loads of rooms that are just empty i
plan on making one room at a time so
what we need to begin with is a basic
building
and a meeting room so that's exactly
what i've done and what's really funny
and i'm pretty sure if i didn't say
anything i'd get a lot of comments about
it anyway
i built this island to build it on
and then i mean
it barely even touches the island that i
made for this specific purpose this
island has absolutely no purpose i could
have just had this straight out of the
water but because i i thought of this
like second compared to this so
ah
silly really silly but this might come
in useful a little later on who knows
let's go and take a little ins
let's go take a look inside there's no
entrance other than flying in on the
landing pad that i've made here there's
like a balcony out on the ocean it's a i
think it looks quite nice
but inside we've got a very basic room
inside mumbo's mustache we've got two
chairs one for me and one for the future
mayor himself
and then we've got our campaign plan
yeah that's
that's kind of what i got for now mumbo
for mayor
poster it took me a long time to make
this so we better get good use out of it
and then of course some small
decorations either side because without
these decorations without this
you would not be able to see anything
you can't differentiate in fact if i go
in here without any blocks in here it's
really difficult to tell
where they are because they just super
blend in and look if i just get rid of
the light now normally you can see
blocks but look at that
it might as well be an infinity room
because if i place a block suddenly you
can see where we are if i remove these
boom
it's so dark in here building with black
concrete is actually really difficult
just because it's hard to see where
there is a gap there boom so the next
thing to do is actually tell mumbo that
we need to have a meeting he has no idea
of course that we've even started at
headquarters i'm pretty sure he doesn't
even know what mumbo for mayor is all
about i actually really like this it's
super simple but it is it is what it is
this is this is what it is
this building shows exactly what it is
by being what it is all right let's go
back to the base wait a second what is
this monstrosity of a shot welcome to
the ugly torch you got that right what
is this all products sell for redstone
blocks they're selling a decent amount
of products oh
there are some things in here that i
could definitely get uh looks like
someone might have beaten me to it for
the most part but since i can trade for
redstone blocks that could be a really
good investment so now we gotta go and
tell um mustached mare that is meeting
time
halfway you know i'm one day i'm just
gonna wait here and just and just get it
i have myself some signs
oh my goodness
mumbo's been making
some crazy bit of his base
that's quite the contrast i like it but
where do i leave the signs there you go
there's there's his bed so why don't we
just pop the signs
right here i wonder if he reads these in
my voice
mayor mumbo
mumbo i don't know if you know but you
are kind of being campaigned for by me
to be mayor i maybe should have told you
about it but it's too late now i made a
hq and would like to have a meeting as
soon as you can let me know and meet me
at the family
that's a hard word to say familiarly
shaped building off the coast of the
shopping district past the concrete
shops g
that should be clear enough for mumbo to
find us when he's next online
we'll meet up and we will discuss the
very pressing matter
of ruling the diamond throne
hopefully with a mustache
but unfortunately that is all we have
time for today things have progressed a
lot i have done an extreme amount of
building not just mumbo's hq
but also
this
the interior of my base and i'm kind of
glad that i got it out the way
earlier rather than later
because i usually ignore the interior
until the very last second but i think
this has gone quite well and i still
want to know what you think in the
comments and also i'd like to know what
you think of the mumbo hq because it's
just the start but it's going to get way
bigger
so thank you very much for watching of
course and i shall see you in the next
episode and again another thank you to
everyone that donated to our charity
live stream thank you very much watching
and good bye